Alexander Kasem

Software Engineer

As a software engineer, I endeavor to work on projects that require a synergy of logic, analytical methodologies, and creativity. I have experience in entrepreneurial development, product development / design, as well as tabletop game design. I have honed my leadership skills through the military and research acumen while earning a bachelors of science degree in applied psychology.

I endeavor to become a seasoned software engineer by continuing to learn new concepts as well as iterating upon what I already know.



€ ∨

Work History

Address

New York Metropolitan Area

Phone

908-763-2983

E-mail

code@pondermint.com



Javascript

React.js

Python 3

Django

Flask

HTML5

CSS3

Node.js

Express.js

MongoDB

Mongoose

2020-07 -

Current Gener

General Assembly

Completed General Assembly's software engineering immersive bootcamp. Programmed:

Software Engineering Immersive Fellow

- War Card Game: HTML5, C\$\$3, JavaScript (vanilla).
- Board Game Collector App: Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, Heroku.
- Project Manager (team project): React.js,
 Semantic UI (React), MongoDB, CSS3, Heroku.
- Skill / Objectives tracker: Python, Django,
 PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Heroku.

2017-11 -

Current

Founder / Company Owner

Ponder Mint LLC, Blairstown, N.I.

- Took concept from inception to sellable product.
- Designed, initiated and ran crowdfunding campaign on a major platform.
- Initiated operational improvements using lean methodologies to drive efficiency and reduce costs.

2017-11 -Current Founder / Company Owner

Ponder Enterprises LLC, Blairstown, NJ

 Established storefront on a major e-commerce platform.

PostgreSQL Heroku Github Bootstrap Semantic UI React Problem solving skills	2019-04 - 2020-05	 Manufacture and distribute company products. Charitable for-profit structure. Fiber Optics Technician Micro-Optics, Inc, Blairstown, NJ Performed tests on passive fiber optic components. Participated in specialized fiber optic component assembly.
Research methodology Excellent written communication skills Meticulous attention to	2015-10 - 2017-04	Consumer Electronics Prep / Auditing Technician Computer Wholesalers Inc • Audited / inspected consumer electronics, prior to resale.
Ability to work independently Active learner Experienced team player Assimilation and	2012-05 - 2016-06	 Officer Candidate New Jersey Army National Guard, Sea Girt, NJ Army Officer Candidate School tactical leadership training and assessments. Army Basic Combat Training, Ft. Leonard Wood, MO.

Education

condensing of complex

information

Certificate of Completion: Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly

Bachelor of Science: Applied Psychology

East Stroudsburg University Of Pennsylvania - East Stroudsburg, PA

Social Science

Ajou University - Suwon, South Korea